I'm not gonna hold back.
I warned the others
that I wouldn't.
Recording it like this
is so important to us.
I guess it's our way of telling
ourselves that we matter.
That we mean something.
Maybe...
some of the things we've done...
and the friends that we've lost...
hopefully it all makes
a difference somehow.
There's only one way to do this.
And that's to go back
to where it all began.
TOMORROW WHEN THE WAR BEGAN
What, with Kevin? When?
Last night. He came over
to help with the shearing.
Some sheep got out
and dad went after them.
We were all by ourselves
for, like, 20 minutes.
You did it in a shearing shed?
-In the bed of soft pure merino wool.
My God, you're such a nympho.
You can talk, Ellie. What about you
and Steve at rehearsals last year.
Oh please, we never went that far.
-Now... pinky swear not to tell.
Pinky swear? Is that not something
we stopped doing in second grade?
Corrie's been my best mate
for as long as I can remember.
Whenever I had a problem,
I'd go tell Corrie
and somehow, she'd always fix it.
So, how was it?
-Well, not how I expected.
I feel different somehow.
Like a real woman.
I wanna do more, see more.
I wanna be more.
What would you wanna do?
How about a trip before
we get back to school?
We haven't been
at the river in ages. -Sure.
Maybe dad will let us
have a Land rover.
Maybe Kevin can come with us?
I see. You'd like to have more sex,
is that it? -No... Well, yeah.
Look, we'll get a bunch
of us together and...
if your dad lets us
have a Land rover,
we should go further up the river
than we've ever been before.
Even up to Taylor's Stitch.
And all the way into Hell.
Hell is on the other side of
Taylor's Stitch. Nobody goes there.
Yes. Why don't you go up the
river again? You always loved that.
Because we wanna go somewhere
we haven't gone before.
Make it a real adventure.
-Why Land rover? Why not the bikes?
Or horses even. Like in an old
fashioned camp out. That'd be fun.
Guys, I'm not ten anymore.
Besides, if there was an emergency,
wouldn't you prefer that I had Land rover?
I don't know, Ellie.
It's a pretty big ask.
Like it or not, dad,
I'm turning 18 this year.
Don't you think it's time
I started showing initiative and...
independence and all those
other good things?
C'mon. It's just a couple of days.
What's the worst
that could possibly happen?
But the show is on this weekend.
-So what?
Do you really care if your mom
wins best decorated cake?
Flip!
I always pictured Kevin in 20 years
being president of the Show Society,
and bringing up his 3 kids.
-Alright.
With Corrie, if she got her way.
-Anything for you.
And she usually did.
Please, tell him he can go to
the bloody show if he wants to.
There's plenty of guys
who'd kill to come with us.
Come on, who else can we ask?
-Somebody fun.
Homer.
I'll see you next weekend, sunshine.
Homer grew up on the farm next to mine.
He was kind of like a brother to me.
He was always getting into trouble.
Both in school and out.
The new police sergeant
arrested him 3 times in one week.
Hey, sarge, how're you going?
Good?
That didn't slow down Homer.
-Alright. -Yeah?
How's the wife, is she good?
I think it was the proud
rebellious greek side of him.
He just didn't care what he did.
Or what anyone thought of him.
How about it?
Are you in or are you out?
Yeah, I'll have a go at that.
Just you girls going?
-Yeah, and Kevin. -It'll be good
for you to have a man around.
To do all the hard work for you.
Well, that's four. Anyone else?
What about Fiona Maxwell?
Fifi, out in the bush? Seriously?
Oh gosh! You really want me?
Fi was the only person I knew
under 60 who said 'gosh'.
Well, no. But our parents said
we had to bring someone along
with a little bit of class.
To balance out all us inbred rurals.
She lived in town,
but we liked her anyway.
Okay. Give me a sec
and I'll ask mom.
Mommy, can I please go camping
with the girls this weekend?
Camping, out in the bush? Seriously?
I'll admit it, Lee was an odd choice.
He was always working in his mom
and dad's restaurant, or of course...
... playing piano.
Everyone else thought he was strange.
I just thought he was interesting.
May I take your order?
-No, sorry, I don't wanna order anything.
Is this for pick-up or for take-away?
No, I would like to speak to
your son Lee. Is he available?
You have menu? -No. Yes I do,
but I don't wanna order anything.
What you want?
-I want Lee.
Your son Lee.
I want Lee.
-This is Lee.
Good evening.
This is Ellie Linton.
I sat next to you in geography
last year. It was on tuesdays.
I have... sort of longish dark hair.
-Yeah, I know who you are, Ellie.
Good. Well, some
friends of mine and I are...
We're skipping the show this weekend
and we're going camping instead.
I was... We were wondering if...
maybe... if you wanted to...
... come with us? Or not?
No, that would be awesome.
-Really?
Oh, good. I'll put you down then.
It was actually... -My mom
makes me go help out now.
Can you text me the details?
Yes, I can...
Yes. I'll do that.
Alright. See you.
-B... bye.
Lee made it six. But dad said
we had to have eight.
Eventually we compromised on 7,
as long as Robyn was the 7th.
Sorry, Robyn.
If it was just you girls...
... but with boys?
Not without an adult present.
Of course, if parents ever had a daughter
they could trust, it was Robyn.
Well, the boys will be
in separate tents, dad.
And besides,
this camping trip isn't about...
... romance or anything. It's more
about getting back to nature.
You know, we're all kind of...
cooped up in this modern environment,
and I think this camping trip
will help me to help my friends
become closer to God.
Because we need to share
a spiritual connection.
If parents were present, I don't think
that I'd be able to reach these girls.
And these boys
as much as I would like to.
Are you alright, Fi?
You're looking a bit pale.
You look like you're gonna...
It's stuck in the back
of your throat, isn't it?
You're trying
to swallow it all down.
But it just keeps coming back up.
Okay, I got it.
How much stuff do you need?
-Oh my God Ellie, look at this!
Wait, what is this? Makeup?
You never know
who you're going to meet.
Hey, you can see
Cobbler's Bay from here.
You can even see the Heron Bridge.
How far do you reckon we've come?
-That was the easy part.
From here on, we walk.
Ready? On the count of three. One...
Give me a decent throw, sweetheart.
Let's go.
I meant to do that.
Homer, do you even know
where we're going?
There's a clearing up ahead.
This is very pretty for Hell.
I wonder how long it's been
since anyone's been down here.
I wonder if anyone has
ever been down here, I mean...
why would anyone else've bothered?
-Maybe we're the first ones to see it.
There's no reception. -What were
you expecting, broadband?
Couldn't hurt.
You, what's your name.
Go get some firewood, will you?
It's Lee.
Ellie, what are we having for dinner?
Two-minute noodles.
-Oh, great!
What are they?
You've never heard
of two-minute noodles?
No, my mom is really
into health foods.
It's an awesome feeling to realise you're
about to change someone's life forever.
You haven't got 2000 dollars.
Wait a sec, not one guy
asked you out last year?
No. Why would they?
Why? You're beautiful, Fi.
My mom is beautiful.
I'm just...
You remember, I had braces
for like two years.
I still wear glasses and it's not...
She was Miss Wirrawee
three years in a row.
I actually asked her
if I should enter this year,
but she didn't think
that was a good idea.
Anyway, I'm doing really well
at school at the moment, so...
... doesn't matter.
And, you know,
a guy will ask me out one day.
I just don't know when. Or who.
Which is exciting.
Boys are idiots.
-Fun idiots.
You shall not pass.
What's that smell?
-Jet fuel.
-What?
Just a bunch of army planes
going somewhere.
El, what do you think of Fi?
I love Fi, you know that.
She seems so perfect.
I guess she thinks
I'm a total loser, huh?
I don't think she hates you.
-Yeah, but... you know.
She lives in that big house.
Talks like Mrs Hamilton.
Me and my family... we are just
greek peasants to people like her.
Why don't you ask her out?
I don't know.
Girl as pretty as that
must get asked out all the time.
Did anyone else hear
those planes last night?
Yeah. There was six lots of them.
They were flying really low.
No, there were dozens and dozens.
We were counting them, Lee and me.
Lee and I. -But seriously, what do
you think those planes were doing?
Maybe they weren't even ours.
It's probably the start of World
War Three and we don't even know.
Alright, who's having rabbit?
Is there any chocolate left?
-Sadly, we're all out.
Oh look, I found some.
-Don't be a dickhead. Give it back!
Thank you. Kevin?
-I was gonna give you some.
So beautiful out here.
I wonder why they call it Hell.
I guess cause it's so wild
and untamed and stuff. Right?
Right.
Wild is difficult.
And it's wonderful and fascinating.
But it's not Hell. People call it that.
People stick labels on things.
Until nobody can see them for who
or what they really are anymore.
Hey, what's going on? -There's
a bloody snake in my sleeping bag.
Are you sure, mate?
I can't see anything.
What kind of snake was it?
-I didn't look.
Lot of red bellies out here.
-Are they deadly?
No. Well... if they bite you.
Shake it.
The bag, Beyonce.
Don't lift it too high.
I got it, I got it!
I was just about
to do that myself.
Christ, that's a big one!
Are you alright?
-Yeah.
Thanks.
I'm not sleeping in that bag
again. Jesus Christ!
-No need to swear.
-Kevin, no need to bloody swear.
Is it dead?
-Looks dead. Wait...
Nobody's laughing, Homer.
Hey, Fi. Why did you go
into the river?
To get away from
the snake, of course.
You do know that snakes
can swim, right? -No, they can't.
-Yeah they can.
-Snakes can't swim.
They don't have fins. They slither.
-They slither through water.
-No, they don't.
-What about sea snakes?
Oh my God!
I could've died!
Oh, Fifi!
Can I go home now?
Do we have to go back?
Well, I'm excited about
a hot shower. And a pillow.
A pillow would be nice.
Let's do this again.
Back here in the same place.
-With the same people.
-If we can find it again.
-We'll find it again.
Let's keep it quiet or
everyone will start coming here
and the place will be
wrecked in no time.
Ladies and gentlemen...
and Homer.
To Hell!
-To Hell.
-Cheers.
Ellie, what's with your dog?
-Millie!
Mom! Mom?
Dad! Hallo!
Where are you parents?
-I don't know.
-Maybe they left a note.
-Did they say they were going away?
-What's the story, El?
-I've no idea. They should be here.
-Let's ring my parents.
-No, ring Homer's. They're closer.
There's no dial tone.
-What?
What about TV?
Maybe your grandmother got sick so
they left... -And cut the phone lines?
-Some big electrical problem?
-No, they wouldn't leave Millie to...
Oh, stinks! -Power must be out.
I'll check the generator.
Where's your laptop?
-Shit!
-Ellie, let's go to Homer's.
-Ellie...
-What?
-Maybe not a good idea.
-Stop the car. Let me out!
Mama! Papa!
Wait, where's Lee going? Lee?
What are you doing?
We shouldn't leave it in the open.
-Remember the planes?
We weren't in the open.
Are you serious?
Homer?
I already tried that.
Real quiet out there.
-Did you send out a call?
Wouldn't be safe.
No! I know what you're thinking
and it's not possible.
Absolutely, completely impossible.
That kind of stuff just doesn't
happen here. Not in this country.
We gotta be careful.
It could be a lot at stake here.
She's right. We've got to assume
something bad has happened.
Of course something bad
has happened. My dog is dead.
-I didn't mean it like that.
-Shut up! Everyone shut up!
Jesus Christ, what is going on?
Kevin's place was next.
I don't remember who suggested it,
but we decided to
stay off the main roads.
Mom! Dad! Mitchell!
Flip?
Flip!
Looks alright. -He always has a bucket
of food and some water. Don't you, boy?
You can't bring that.
You think I'm just gonna leave
him here? I'm not leaving him!
Stop it!
I'm not leaving him!
He's got a point.
Let's take Flip to Corrie's and then
we can make another decision
depending on what we
find there. Agreed?
Flip, let's go.
C'mon.
That's four out of four.
The rest of you live in town.
Robyn's house is on Coachman's
Lane. That's probably the closest.
Yeah, you can see most of Wirrawee
from the hill at the back.
It might tell us something.
-Then we go to Robyn's next.
Flip, sit. Stay.
Please don't touch that.
-Let's go up that hill.
Something's going on
at the Showground.
I think that's where everyone is.
-What about those other lights?
Hospital. Must be using
the emergency generators.
Maybe we should split up.
Split up? No, we can't.
We have to stay together.
We need to be out of town
before dawn. Just in case.
I'll take Fi to her house.
Lee, you take Robyn to yours.
We'll meet back here at 5 a.m.
So we just stay here?
You get to go to the Show.
Whose voices are those?
-I don't know.
I think we should go back.
-No. Wait.
We have to get a better
look before we leave.
Better look at what, Ellie?
Let's go!
One of us has to get closer before
we go. We gotta see what's going on.
I'm not leaving Corrie here.
-I'll go.
-Ellie!
If anything happens, run.
Do not try to escape
or you will be shot.
Dad!
This is bloody ridiculous. I've been
waiting in this stupid line for 2 hours!
Who do you people think you are?
Hands off me.
Are you okay?
Where's Kevin?
Quick! They're coming!
Ellie... -What?
-Can we stop?
Corrie, c'mon! Please! Please.
Come on.
Where are they now?
-I don't know. -Guys!
Kevin! Oh my God!
What happened to you?
I thought that you're ahead of me,
so I just... I just ran.
Ellie said that if anything
was to happen to run.
-Oh my God!
-Go!
C'mon, c'mon...
Let's go.
-I hurt my knee.
-C'mon, we gotta keep moving.
Are you alright?
-No. I cut it. Jesus!
Give me your shirt. Quick.
Singlet, it's better. Quick.
Get me a stick or something.
Stay here.
Ellie, hurry up!
Quick, get back!
-Will this do?
-Yeah, quick.
Ellie, they are coming.
-Alright.
Light it.
Corrie, we gotta get out of here.
Get up, c'mon. Ellie, let's go!
Hang up.
She wasn't much older than I was.
And she looked just as scared.
I'll never forget her.
Ellie, we don't have time.
-Come on!
Thank God!
We heard an explosion.
-Yeah, that was us.
-Are you alright? -Yeah.
Flip! There he is. Good boy!
Where did all those
soldiers come from?
Where did you get this thing?
Wait, where's Robyn and Lee?
They haven't come back yet.
-It's almost 6 a.m.
We were just about
to give up on all of you.
We have to go and find them
then, don't we? -Ellie...
Homer, we have to go find them.
-It's daylight now.
-I'm not leaving them.
-We're not leaving them.
We'll come back tonight
when it's safer.
Yeah cause there'll be soldiers
crawling all over town by now.
I mean... after what you did.
We will find them.
Ellie, I promise.
El... El... come on.
-Wait, just...
-No, don't touch me.
Sit down over there.
-Are you alright?
I'll get us some food.
-Thank you.
So, any idea whose army it is?
-We didn't exactly stop to ask.
We'll ask Robyn. She's good
with flags and things like that.
All I can say is they are not greek.
-It doesn't matter who they are,
because they're here.
We just got to deal with it.
Alright, mate. Calm down.
No, seriously, what difference
does a flag make?
Fi made this for you.
Her house is empty too?
-Yeah.
There are soldiers everywhere.
We crawled all the way
back to Robyn's.
Not bad for a first date.
The others told me what happened.
El.
It's not your fault.
It's theirs.
It's all theirs.
You're changing.
-Yeah?
-For better or worse?
-Better. Definitely better.
Looks good.
Fi'd always say
she'd be a doctor.
You're gonna have to forgive him
sooner or later, you know.
He just left us, Ellie.
He just ran and left us.
I thought he loved me.
Do you remember how many
hours we used to spend up here?
You mean the tea parties?
We were so innocent
back then. And now I...
I feel like we were innocent
right up until yesterday.
We didn't believe in Santa Claus
or anything like that.
You know, we believed
in other fantasies.
We believed we were safe.
I guess that was the biggest
fantasy of them all, right?
Do you ever think we'll see
Robyn and Lee again?
That's one of ours!
How many planes do we have?
One less now.
How's this?
I'm going to Wirrawee with Ellie
and we look for Robyn and Lee.
You three go back to my place
and load up the Land rover.
Seems a hell of a risk
going back into Wirrawee.
What if it was you
they're going back for?
Don't ask me to go with you.
-He's not.
Good, because
I'm not bloody going.
Jesus, Kevin. Everything is
a risk from now on.
We can't sit around here forever.
The biggest risk is to take no risk.
Alright. But if we can't stay here
where do you want us all to go?
Hell.
We're not taking your teddies.
-Not all of them, just one.
We can't take things like that.
-Why can't we?
This isn't a picnic, El. We have
to start acting like soldiers.
One mistake and... it's all over.
Can we take my mom's crowns and sashes?
-Yeah, and photos. Don't forget photos.
Geez, we're gonna need
a trailer pretty soon.
Look, if you can take teddies,
crowns and photos,
I might aswell take my dad's
bloody football trophies.
Oh, and dog food for Flip.
Lots of dog food. Write that down.
-He can eat rabbit.
-What about wire cutters?
Now that's a great idea.
Two T's.
What about guns?
-We'll take our own guns.
Just turn it off.
-No, I can fix this. Hang on.
The pipe's burst again.
So, we've got plenty of
ammo for the rifles,
and a full magazine for that.
I got it!
What's that?
We forgot to have someone on watch.
Don't touch the curtains.
Spread out!
Go into different rooms.
If you see anything, yell out.
But stay hidden.
Flip!
Flip, get inside!
It's here!
Did they see you?
-I don't know.
Homer!
Ellie!
Stay still!
Good thing you're so skinny.
Hey guys, I think it's coming back.
Flairs. They're marking the house.
-Thanks a lot, Homer.
-No one asked your opinion, mate.
They know we're here now. -Of course they
know. They saw us through the window.
But they didn't know we had guns!
Let's get out of here.
C'mon, let's get out of here, now!
Go, go, go...
Go, go, move it!
Run!
-Flip!
Leave him!
-No!
Homer was right.
Hell was the only
safe place for us now.
But first we had to find
Robyn and Lee.
What's wrong?
-The Heron Bridge!
Jesus, look at them all.
They are coming up from
Cobbler's Bay.
I bet you this is one of
the first places they captured.
It's probably
full of ships right now.
Yeah. And our bridge
gives them direct access to it.
I've always hated that bridge.
Come on, we have to
get to Robyn's house.
Robyn!
Ellie?
How did you know it was her?
-That's her dad's walking stick.
What was she gonna do,
beat us with it?
Ellie, thank God!
-Are you hurt?
-No, no, I'm fine.
Where is Lee?
He's been shot.
Wait here a minute.
Someone should go with her.
All clear. Let's go.
Robyn. Go, go, go...
Don't point that thing at me.
-This is dr Clement.
It's okay, he's my dentist.
He works across the street.
-Dr Clement, it's me. It's Robyn.
-Quiet down, the lot of you.
Don't you know there's
a bloody war going on?
Shine that here.
How is it? -He was lucky.
The bullet went right through.
Thank you. -You picked the hell
of a weekend to go camping.
We heard the planes,
but we didn't see any...
That's how they did it.
Freighter planes and container ships.
Took all the ports and runways
in the first 24 hours.
News said there was some
kind of explosion at the airfield.
None of us paid much attention to it.
Next thing you know,
they are rolling across the bridge
in their tanks and trucks,
rounding up everyone, taking
them all to the Showground.
Lee's whole family.
Yours too.
And mine? -Yours I don't
know anything about.
What about my parents?
George and Martha Yannos.
Did they ever get
their teeth fixed? -No.
Then how the hell would I know who
they are? -I was just asking, doc.
I've been hiding in the closet
for three straight days,
living in my own piss and shit, just
waiting for them to come and find me.
I thought I'll finally snap when
I saw you carrying Lee in here.
-You carried him?
-Yeah, I had to.
If his leg starts to hurt,
you gotta give him another shot.
Wait, you're not staying with us?
Look, I took a hell of a risk
coming down here for Lee, alright?
I've done enough.
I've gotta go.
Wait, dr Clement. Are there
any others out there? Like us?
Oh, yeah. I've seen few people
try to do some things.
Try to be heroes.
Apparently one group even
tried to blow up Heron bridge.
To stop all those bloody convoys
coming up from Cobbler's Bay.
They all paid the price.
Are you okay?
I think we should get a vehicle.
-We always had two.
First one you dump somewhere.
Second one is a getaway car.
-So, you had practice at this?
-Great. I'll just go get mom's car,
park it at the front and ask soldiers
to look the other way, shall I?
Sorry. I'm just... tired.
How about if we get
something silent?
Golf carts, shopping trollies...
-Prams, pushers...
Wheelchairs? -Yeah, could you
ride in a wheelchair?
I could, but the more I move
the more it hurts. -Wait...
What if we're going about this
the wrong way?
What do you mean?
We're thinking of quiet
sneaky little things, right?
What if we went
to the other extreme?
Rock up in something so indestructible
that it wouldn't matter who saw us.
Such as?
Shit!
Let's go!
Are you alright?
-Hang on. -What?
-I can't climb up there.
-Get in the bucket.
-In this?
-Yeah.
I thought you said
you could drive this thing.
I said I can drive a tractor.
Get in.
Oh shit.
Drive, Ellie. Drive!
Take this, shoot back at them!
-No, I won't do it.
This is no time to get religious.
-I said no!
You're bleeding!
Go!
I hope Homer's got a getaway car.
-I hope he remembers where to meet us.
Even Homer knows how to
find a bloody church. -Ellie!
Start praying again.
Lord, forgive us our sins...
Hold on!
I think we lost one of them.
We lost a tire!
You're driving in circles!
-I'm doing the best I can!
You are dangerous. -That's what
my driving instructor said.
He's still chasing us!
How do you dump the rubbish?
-That switch, I think.
Who is dangerous now?
-Do you think any of them got hurt?
Don't worry.
God will understand.
Where's Homer?
He's supposed to be here.
Where is he?
Maybe he got caught.
We have to keep going,
get out of town.
No. Ellie, we've got
to wait for Homer.
How long do you think it's gonna be
before they send another vehicle?
Or even a helicopter?
We have to leave now!
Sorry I'm late. I forgot
where the bloody church was.
Why are we stopping?
-I have to rest.
Move over, I'll drive.
-No, dad said only I...
Just don't, okay?
This is Chris Lang's house.
Oh, that guy is such a weirdo.
-He's a genius, Kevin.
-He's a bloody stoner.
-Stoners are people too.
I don't really care as long as
there's a soft bed in there.
And maybe a toothbrush.
-I've got a spare toothbrush.
Chris says his father was born on
the corner of Straight and Narrow.
And that he was born
in the other end of town.
The day before it all began,
mom and dad left for Saudi Arabia.
So, here I am. Alone.
And the power
goes off at like nine...
... or ten. Nine.
Yeah, nine.
So I think, okay.
I better ring up and
find out what's going on.
I'm an idiot.
The phones are down too.
So, I'm so bent by this point.
Like, I'm really stoned. I'm baked.
Anyway, I walk down to the car...
... and dad, get this right,
dad has locked the car
and taken the keys with him.
I think he's such a wanker
for doing that.
You know, like he didn't even
trust me with a car for one week.
So now, I have to walk
to the Ramseys' place.
And it is far. Like,
take what you think is far,
time it by like 10, say.
And that's how far it was.
And when I get there...
... nobody is at home.
And it's like... oh, great!
Because the next place
is even further.
Anyway, I walk around the corner.
And I can see the Ramseys
in their truck.
They'd hit a tree.
But that's not
what has killed them.
They've been shot.
They've been shot?!
Like no one gets shot.
And I mean, heaps of times.
Mr Ramsey, Mrs Ramsey,
even baby Jessica's been shot.
So, I think to myself...
Either I've been smoking
some really weird shit,
or this isn't your
typical day in Wirrawee.
Anyway, I've just been
by myself ever since, really.
Just chilling out.
It's been nice.
Nice.
How funny are dogs?
How does it feel to get shot?
I didn't even feel it at first.
But by the time I got back
to the restaurant, it felt
like my whole leg was on fire.
Like somebody was pulling
a barbed wire throught it.
They wrecked your restaurant?
Yeah.
I used to hate that place.
Working there, being there.
Just living there.
I felt like I was
in prison or something.
But you know, I helped
make that place what it was.
So when someone smashes a window,
they are smashing glass that
I hand-polished a thousand times.
Or they are tearing curtains
that my mom and I hand-stitched.
You get a certain type
of attachment to the place.
It's weird. Takes on
its own kind of beauty.
You know, I always used to
look forward to geography.
I should go back and
check on Chris. -Chris?
Yeah, I left him on watch.
Sorry.
Chris.
Chris? Hey!
Get up. Get up!
Are you awake now, you little shit?
-Geez Ellie, take it easy.
-Take it easy? -Yeah, I just
shut my eyes for a second.
Don't you understand how it's all
changed, Chris? Don't you get it?
-Yeah, I do. I do get it.
-If we take it easy any more...
We might aswell shoot each other
now and get it over with.
Okay I get it. I do.
I'm sorry.
I'm really really sorry.
Must be that time of the month.
Shoot me. -What are you doing?
-Go on Chris, shoot me!
-I don't wanna shoot you.
-You can't kill me while I'm awake?
-Geez Ellie, it was an accident.
I'm sorry. -Bullshit you're sorry!
People are dying out there, Chris.
Families have been split apart.
We've seen homes
blown to pieces.
Yet you're up here
having a fuckin vacation.
So, go on. Don't wait
for me to fall asleep.
Buck up, be a man, look me
in the eye and pull the trigger.
Ellie, please... -No?
-What are you doing?
Do you know what penalty is
for falling asleep at your post?
Do you know what they
used to do? -No, Ellie...
Ellie!
Put the gun down, please.
I said I'm sorry. Please!
He risked all our lives.
Ellie.
It's Chris.
It's just Chris.
How long have I been asleep?
About 16 hours.
How's Chris?
Still pretty shaken.
You gave him a hell of a fright,
you know.
I'll apologize when he wakes up.
I promise.
Actually, he wants
to apologize to you.
You were right, El.
You went a little overboard
about it, but you were right.
You're a good mate, Corrie.
And you're a bloody nutcase.
-Good book?
-Better than the movie.
Yeah, books usually are.
The general repeated his claim
that the Coalition nations
can no longer support
their booming populations.
And that Australia must be
made to share her vast land
and extensive natural resources
with her less fortunate neighbors.
In this way, general hopes
the invasion will balance
the economic scales
within the region
and eventually lead to a new era
of peace and stability.
Meanwhile, more than
half a million Coalition forces
are pouring into Australia
though three captured ports.
These ports have now being
identified as Townsville,
Port Headland and Cobbler's Bay.
-You heal well.
-I have good genes.
There's something
I've been meaning to ask you.
You know at Chris' house
the other day when I was...
playing with your hair and then...
-Yeah, all right.
I know what we did. -Okay,
I thought you might have forgotten.
What, do you think I do that stuff
so often that I forget about it?
But you've hardly
spoken to me since then.
-I'm just confused.
-About me?
Yeah, about you, about us.
About this war.
About this mess that
we found ourselves in.
The truth is, half the time
I have no idea what I'm doing.
So then, I do these things,
and they don't always mean
what I think they mean.
Do you know what I mean?
No, I've no idea what you mean.
-Okay...
Look, it meant something then
and it does mean something now,
but... I don't think it means
what you'd wanted it to mean.
-Do you just not like me?
-No, Lee. I like you, okay?
I like you very much. But right now,
you're driving me crazy.
I don't know why
I was talking the way I was.
All I really wanted to do is hold him
and tell him that everything
is gonna be alright.
I just didn't know if it was.
None of us did.
All we could say for sure was
that for now, we were free.
But we've done nothing
to earn our freedom.
Not yet, anyway.
The way I see it,
these are our choices.
One: we can sit here
and do nothing.
Come out when the war's over.
I don't know about you guys...
but I'm not so good
at doing nothing.
Two: we can all try to be heroes.
Rescue our families
from the Showgrounds.
But like dr Helpful said,
we'll probably pay the price.
Or three: we can go out there,
at night. Guerrilla style.
Using hit and run tactics
and take back Wirrawee.
Maybe even help win this thing.
-Yeah, you're right.
We were born here. We know
this country better than they do.
We can use that to our advantage.
Plant traps, ambush them, pick them off.
-You're talking about murder.
-It's not murder if it's in a war.
What about the Bible, "thou shall
not kill". What about that?
David killed Goliath. -That doesn't
apply in a situation that is a metaphor.
Do you think it's fair, do you?
-No. -Just let them walk in,
take everything they want and
our parents worked so hard for?
No Kevin, I don't think it's fair.
I don't think it's fair at all.
Are you in or are you out?
Well, I feel like I should be out.
But I can't stop thinking
about the coincidence that...
from all the weekends that
we could've chosen to go camping,
we chose that weekend.
God spared us for a reason.
And I think he wants us
to do something.
So I will help you Homer, but
I'm not going to murder anybody.
All this talk scares me
to death, but...
I think we have to
fight back anyway.
We'll never sleep again if we don't.
-We'll never sleep again if we did.
-What are you chicken, Chris?
-You'd know all about that, wouldn't you?
There's nothing chicken
about staying alive, mate.
We're not even trained for this stuff.
What would our parents say?
They'd say the most important
thing is our safety.
They wouldn't want us dead
in exchange for them being alive.
I suppose when the time comes,
I'll do what I have to do.
What worries me though is that...
I can't guarantee that I'm not
gonna pack up under pressure.
I'm so scared and...
I think that I might just
stand there and scream.
None of us knows how we're gonna
react when shit hits the fan.
You've done alright so far.
Well, for a townie.
We have to do something.
I'm not just gonna sit here.
And do nothing.
I'm different to all of you.
I have blood on my hands.
I can't tell if what I did
was right or wrong.
I'd like to think it was
to save my friends,
or as part of some noble
crusade to save my country.
Really it just comes down to the fact
that I valued my life over theirs.
How many people is it okay to kill
in order to keep me alive?
At what point do we lose our souls,
if we haven't already?
In the end I think we just
have to trust our instincts.
After all, it is all
we have left, isn't it?
What do your instincts tell you?
That it's time to go to war.
What are we gonna do?
Blow it up?
Cobbler's Bay is
one of their key ports.
And this bridge
is the only way in or out.
It's the key to everything.
If they can't resupply their soldiers,
then they can't fight.
They've got sentries. -We have
to find the way to distract them.
Remember what dr Clement said?
About how other people tried to
blow up that bridge before?
Amateurs.
Couple of years ago
me and some mates
came up with the way to take
this bridge down. Just for fun.
That's hardly reassuring,
knowing your mates.
Can you drive a petrol tanker?
-Hurry up.
-Okay.
Sorry.
-Big one?
-The big one.
There! They are there.
In the window.
Wait! -What?
-Can I do it?
I've always wanted
to smash a window.
-One more.
-Fi! Just...
Do it!
Fi, run!
Stop!
Turn around!
Do not move!
-Guys, are you there?
-We're all set. We can see you.
Don't come any closer. Wait there
till we get the word from Homer.
Lee and me are almost there.
-Lee and "I".
Okay, we're in the position too.
I can see 10 soldiers on the bridge.
We've only got about 15 minutes
before the next convoy comes along.
We'll call you when we're ready.
-Okay honey, we'll be waiting.
Did you just call him 'honey'?
-Homer. I called him 'Homer'.
No, you just called him 'honey'.
-I didn't. -Yes you did, I heard you.
It may have sounded like 'honey'
but I definitely said 'Homer'.
-Go. Go.
-You gotta hiss like a snake.
No, no, like a snake.
So, princess Fifi has the hots
for a rough as guts Homer.
Have you kissed him?
-Would you mind if I had?
Me? Are you serious?
Of course not.
I just know that
you two are close.
-No, never like that.
-Okay, good.
Well then, yes I have.
Is he a good kisser?
Actually no, I don't wanna know.
Don't tell me. It's kinda gross.
-He's a great kisser.
-Great. Now I know.
But he's so down on himself.
He's got this weird thing
about my parents being lawyers.
And he always used
to joke about it.
But I don't think
he's really joking at all.
Jesus, Fi, how long did it take to
figure that out? -What do you mean?
You know the kind of guys
he knocks about. They're just...
more at home hanging out at the pub
than playing croquet
with your parents.
My parents don't play croquet.
Ellie. Ellie!
Fi! Behind you!
Homer is like two people.
He's so confident with a group,
and then he's super shy with me.
I just don't understand.
Ellie?
If I could understand Homer
I'm sure I'd understand all guys.
Like Lee?
How did you know about that?
-C'mon Ellie, everybody knows.
God, this is worse than recess.
They can't hear us.
Homer, you have to go now.
-But we're still not ready.
There are soldiers creeping up behind
tanker and Ellie's not answering me.
Ellie, pick up.
Just think about it. The eight of us
are living out in the bush.
And the entire world is
completely turned upside down.
I'd just hate to be
responsible for ruining
whatever little good we did have
by Lee and me having a falling out.
Look, Ellie. I'm no expert
on relationships or anything.
But I do know that
you have this tendency
to reason everything
through all the time,
and I just think
the future is the future.
It has to take care of itself.
And by the way, it's Lee and 'I'.
Get out of the truck!
Move! Drive!
Here goes the brilliant plan.
Ellie, I'm so sorry I turned it off.
-Doesn't matter.
Here.
Go!
Ellie, we need the lighter.
-You were to bring it.
No, you were to bring the lighter.
I don't have it.
Christ, the soldiers!
Where the hell is Kevin going?
Robyn, we can't get to you.
-Don't worry about us, just go!
You guys take this one.
Corrie, you're with me.
Run Homer, let's go!
Hurry up, they're coming!
C'mon!
Kevin!
Corrie? Corrie!
Get away!
Come on.
Wait!
Gosh!
It was so much bigger than I expected.
-That's the biggest joint I've ever lit.
Did you see the bridge?
Corrie! Oh my God, what happened?
She got shot as
we were driving away.
I can't...
I can't stop the bleeding.
We'll take her to
go see dr Clement.
He can fix her the same way
that he fixed Lee.
-She needs a hospital, Fi.
-I'm gonna get the Land rover.
-Ellie...
-Hey. Hey!
You have to leave me.
No, I'm not leaving you.
-She's right.
It sounds cruel, but the only thing
to do is ring the bell and run.
-What?
-No!
-No I can't leave her. I won't.
-We have to be rational about this.
If we take her to the hospital,
we will get caught.
No, I don't give a shit
what's rational. Alright?
Corrie is our mate.
She is our mate. And I...
I love her.
I'm taking her in.
I'm staying with her.
I'm staying.
Good luck, mate.
I'll come get you when
you're better. Okay?
Pinky swear.
We've hit them.
Hit them hard.
They are gonna be coming after us
now with everything they've got.
And they did come after us.
For three weeks now,
we've seen...
dozens of planes and helicopters
and search parties.
But they haven't found us yet.
Which means Corrie and Kevin
have told them nothing.
A month ago, we were just
an average bunch of teenagers.
Studying for school and
complaining about our parents.
Now we're soldiers.
Trapped behind enemy lines
and fighting to survive.
We won't run.
We won't hide.
We'll fight and keep fighting.
And never give up.
Until this war is finally won.